John Blazic

115 Greenpoint Avenue Brooklyn, NY 11222 | (513) 504-3183 | johnvblazic@gmail.com https://github.com/johnvblazic

Summary:

A master's student with 5 years of professional experience in data engineering, data warehousing, and ETL design. Possesses a strong desire to get involved with projects using cutting edge techniques and technology in NLP, machine learning, and AI.

Skills:

- Python
- Scala/Java
- Bash/Linux Shell
- D3 & JavaScript

- RDBMS(MySQL, Oracle, MSSQL)
- NoSQL(Hadoop, Hive, CouchDB)
- Docker
- Keras, Numpy, Scipy

Work History:

R&D Engineer - May 2018 - Present -- *FirstAl - New York, New York*

- As a part of the R&D team, I work with our head of engineering to improve our ability to automatically extract information from our clients documents
- Used linguistic analysis libraries to improve ability to extract multiple entities from sentences with complex structure -- negation, use of respectively
- Built a document classifier to identify document classes we and our clients needed, allowing us to ignore more than 40% of what we were previously searching.
- Improved our Elasticsearch performance by 20% through optimization of search structure

Hadoop Programmer - March 2013 - August 2016 -- Regions Financial Corporation - Nashville, TN

- Worked with the operational data store team at Regions to collect data from the multiple lines of business and technical environments that exist within the bank to provide internal customers with a unified data warehouse.
- Built and maintained Java, Bash, Oracle SQL, SAS and HQL code to keep the job engine processing approximately 1 terabyte of data per day.
- Headed internal integration projects: building a DOM for interaction with our system by internal clients; identifying and integrating independent data stores throughout the bank; integrating old SAS code into a modern data warehouse
- Created and maintained dev VMs used to mimic the Hadoop cluster running in production

Junior Software Engineer - Sep 2011 - Dec 2012 -- *Sharable Ink* - Nashville,TN

- Worked primarily within the data analytics team to provide our customers with greater knowledge of their business
- Built end-to-end ETL pipelines; starting with data and requirement collection and finishing with presentations to the CMO of the largest anesthesia group in the country, among others.

Education:

MS - Human Language Technology

May 2018

University of Arizona

• Classwork in NLP, Machine Learning, Data Science, Data Visualization, AI

BA - Classical Languages; History

May 2011

Vanderbilt University

• Classwork in Greek, Latin, Philosophy, History, and Computer Science